hello ladies and gentlemen and welcome
女士们先生们 大家好
my name is Walker Stipe of Palo Alto
我是来自Palo Alto的Walker Stipe
education and today we're gonna be doing
今天我们要来做
some fun stuff we're gonna be
一些有趣的事 我们要来看一看
determining the difference between cars
汽车和杯子之间的差异
so just a Batmobile right here which is
这是一辆蝙蝠车
so cool and cups I don't have an image of cups
很酷吧 至于杯子 我这里没有杯子的图片
so I shall show you an image of
但我有一个杯子可以给大家看一下
a cup this is an image of a cup it's a
我手上是一个杯子
coffee cup at least right now it is
一个普通的咖啡杯 其实我们
it could be filled with anything but the
可以装任何东西进去 但是
moment is filled with coffee so we're gonna
现在里面装的是咖啡 现在
be doing that and we're gonna be yeah
我们就要
we're gonna be doing that that's what
没错
we're doing we're gonna be using machine learning
我们将用机器学习
to determine the difference
来探究汽车
between a car and a cup so we're gonna
和杯子之间的差异 我们要
collect some data collect some pictures
收集一些汽车的数据和图片
of cars whatever cars you want it's up to you
你自己决定要什么样子的车
if you want to the only supercars
你可以只想要超级跑车
I did I only want the fast ones
我就只想要最快的那一辆车
whoopsies and only cups that were dragon cups
哈哈 而杯子就是有龙图案的杯子了
I only use dragon cups because that
我用了这个杯子 因为
was an option to me and I took that option
我只有这一个选择
so we can have some fun with this one
好了 我们来做有趣的事吧
and we will but yeah that's
没错 这就是
that's the goal today so let's jump in
我们今天的目标 我们赶紧
to getting that done to doing that yeah
开始吧！
alrighty so the first step we are gonna
我们要完成
take toward the end of achieving our
这个项目最终目标的
goals for this project is to be getting
第一步就是输入
to the correct website this website is
正确的网站 网址是
machinelearningforkids.co.uk
also known as this guy right here right
也就是屏幕上的这个
yeah boom awesome we got it you can also
你也可以
just type into your google or whatever
在谷歌或其他搜索引擎
machinelearningforkids and it should
machinelearningforkids 这个网站会
be the first option once you're here
会第一个显示出来
welcome first of all I do want you to login
找到网站后希望大家先登陆
don't forget to login it's very important
千万不要忘记登陆啦 这很重要
you're gonna scroll it down to
把网页往下拉一点
the good old fashioned car or cup
看到“好的老式汽车或者杯子”
dude so many options we're gonna pick this one
天哪 我们要挑选这么多选项 我们要选这个
because we're gonna be individuals
因为我们是以个人
and the students we're making this thing
和学生的身份登陆的 而且我们即将要来做这件事
wonderful ladies and gentleman
很棒 女士们先生们
we clicked on the link I hope you clicked
点击链接
on the link and we arrived at this page here
随后我们到达了这个页面
boom yes moving on we see this
哇 这里有很多东西
stuff we're gonna scroll down on
滑动鼠标下拉页面
this is kind of what its gonna look like
这大概就是我们要完成的东西
we are gonna have cars over one side for cups
一边是车子一边是杯子
and we're gonna have all these scripts
还有所有的这些脚本
doing our amazing things over to the other side
来做神奇的事情
yeah we would like to move on
继续往下
to the next portion get our data first
我们要获取数据
we want to make our project so we're
我们要实现我们的项目就要
gonna follow this little process here
遵循这些过程
if you've done an any of these other
如果你已经完成了其他任何一个
projects then you'll know how this works
项目 那么你会知道这是如何运作的
it's gonna go into your projects you're
你要先进入到你的项目里
gonna make one so we're gonna go to
然后我们要
projects we're gonna make a new project
新建一个项目
we're gonna name it kind of whatever you
你可以用任何名字来命名它
want but I named my car or cup
我把它命名为 车或杯子
it's recognizing images awesome awesome
它正在识别图像 太棒了
awesome awesome now we want to train it
现在我们要训练它
right make sure this is good
来确保它是好的
this is where we do this yes this is
往下拉 这里就是
where we do this wonderful all right so
我们要训练它的地方了
it's time to have a good time ladies and gentlemen
女士们先生们 现在
Oh what we're gonna do is
我们要做的是
we're gonna grab awesome pictures from
就是从网页中挑选
the interwebs of cars and cups
汽车和杯子的照片
I must highly recommend to you that you
我强烈推荐你
stick with the car or cup theme because
坚持汽车或杯子的主题，因为
I tried to go to some sci-fi I try to
我试着去尝试一些科幻类型的 我试过
put like two types of aliens the Zerg
把两个类型的外星人 比如异族
and the Protoss from one of my favorite
星灵放在一起 它们都是我最喜欢的
video games
游戏
Starcraft and it didn't know what to do
星际争霸里的 用这两个的时候程序就不知道该怎么做
because this one is looking for cars and
因为它只在寻找汽车和
cups specifically anything else and just
杯子 其他的东西无法
won't work and it would be sad
让它正常工作 这很可惜
so highly recommend you do cars and you do cups
所以我强烈建议你做汽车和杯子
but there's some cool cups out there
而且有些杯子是很酷的
look at these guys we got we got a face cup
看看这些杯子 有的是一张脸
I don't want a face cup
我不想要有一张脸的杯子
there are really cool cups out there
但还是有很多很酷的杯子的
and obviouslythere's some really cool cars
显然还有一些非常酷的车
so cool once we do this well first of all
太酷了 做好这个事情之后
it is awesome quick side note make sure let's
要注意啦
yeah so you don't want to do copy image
我们不是点击复制图像
and I do that you're copying the image address
而是复制图片地址
right and it actually might
没错了 要选“复制图片地址”
take a second just kind of weird and like
有点奇怪 要花一些时间哦
when you go here as we see it's pretty short
然后你点击这个 你会发现它确实很短
46 okay sometimes it would be like 8,000
只有46 好吧有时候会是8000
you're lik e no it's too big I'm only
我们不需要太大的 最多
allowed to do a thousand if it does that
1000就可以啦 如果太大了
just try again its kind of pain but
你就需要重新试一次啦
it should work
应该管用
rock on I hope that you have chosen at
棒 我希望你已经选择了
least 10 tennis and imported at least
并上传了至少十张图片
ten images of each car and each Cup like
每辆车和每个杯子都要有十张图像
total you only need ten images total
总共只需要10张图像
not kind of each that be a hundred and would
不是每一种类都有十张 这样就有一百张图啦
be a lot don't do that
这样就太多了 我们不这么做
all right so once you have done so go
好了 做完之后呢
back to a project and this is where the
我们回到项目里 这就是
magic happens
魔法发生的地方啦
oh my goodness I'm so excited
我的天啊 我很兴奋
we are gonna do the machine learning bit now
我们现在要来进行一些机器学习
which is so cool so we're gonna go back
酷爆了 我们回到
to our projects boom car or cup here it
项目的页面 点击“汽车或杯子”
is learn and test yes and actually need
再点击"学习和测试" 我们需要
to do this because another important
赶紧这样做 因为我们
thing to note is that these things
要注意这些东西
expire
是会过期的呀
right so if you train something yesterday
比如你昨天训练了一些东西
you have your model the next
你建立了你的模型 第二天
day it is probably deleted
它可能已经被删除
and you'll be frustrated
这就很让人难过了
skip that whole shebang and make your
忽略他把 让我们来做
model so we're doing that here
模型吧 我们在这个页面上做
in a moment we will see the screen that we
不一会儿 我们看着屏幕
would like to see that's like hey this
希望看到
worked so while does that we are gonna
它真的成功了 然后我们
go ahead discreetly move awesome
继续
it is doing that it's happening it's waiting
它正在完成 耐心等待
yes yes yes now we're gonna go into scratch
现在我们要进入脚本
if it is complete is it complete
它是否完整呢
it is not complete but it will be in a moment
它并不完整 但是马上它就要完整了
in which case and yes ladies and gentlemen
只要机器训练成功 各位同学
it worked we trained our machine learning model
我们成功啦 我们训练了机器学习模型
and boom here it is the work of our labor
这就是我们辛苦劳动的成果
and while we are waiting
在你等待的时候
we should see a screen such this now
你可以好好看看这个页面
we're gonna go back to scratch
我们先回到脚本
boom here we go we open it up
我们打开它 然后进去
and it looks like this of course it does
它是这个样子的 当然啦
yes alright so we want to open the project templates
我们现在要打开工程模板
we're working on the car or cup dude
就是我们正在做的 车和杯子
pop that open now
现在把它打开
before we do any smooth coding and
我们顺利写代码之前
things such as this try it out all right
我们先试一下
let's see what it does
看看到底会得到什么结果
what you see is that it probably isn't gonna work
大多数情况下 它不会运行
right at the back that's when we hop into
所以我们现在要回到材料中
looking at code we're gonna change right
看看代码 然后对其进行调整
so we need to change some things around
我们需要做出调整
so let's do it we tried it but it doesn't work
因为我们试过了 它不能运行
let‘s change these around we're gonna click
所以我们要进行调整 我们要点击
on our good old mystery sprite mysteries
神秘的老爷车图片
and we're gonna change
我们要调整一下
some things around to look like this
页面要看起来像这个样子
perhaps this is your first time change things around
可能这是你第一次在脚本里面
in scratch that is okay
做一些调整 没关系
perhaps you are not a veteran
你可能是个老手
you know what you're doing
你知道你要做什么
you can move around adeptly adroitly
你可以熟练快速的做到的
other words that mean good yeah
反正你能很好做到
so changed around to look like this
把它调整成这个样子
honest to stick with this
一定要按照这个来
or one could get messed up very possible
不然很容易失败
so once you've done so then kid you not
做完这一步之后
we're just ready we're ready to test it out
我们准备好可以测试啦
so let's do it
让我们试试看吧
full screen we're gonna click the button
全屏 然后点这个按钮
my computer this goes very slowly
这个在我电脑上走的很慢
but as we see it's put a car
但是至少它把一辆车
I believe that this car is a little
一辆小型的电动车
smart cars so cute in the top left
非常可爱 放在左上角
now it's putting all these cups of coffee
现在页面上出现了咖啡
in fact I will join in with my own cup of coffee beans
事实上 现在我也要喝一杯咖啡
coffee is delicious
咖啡非常好喝
and we see that so far it's doing a really good job
到目前为止 我们看到 现在一切都很顺利
all right sweet we have completed our project yes
太棒啦 我们已经完成了我们的项目
maybe it didn't work even though
它可能无法运行
we did everything right
虽然我们做的都是对的
maybe we didn't do everything right
或者 我们犯了错误
we should go back and check just to be sure*3 right
我们得回去检查一下代码 确保无误 对吧
or perhaps there's some other issues
或者是有其他问题
maybe the images you chose
可能是你的电脑
the computer just didn't get
没有办法呈现你选择的图片
maybe you chose such cool cars and such cool mugs but
可能你选择了酷炫的车 酷炫的马克杯
they don't look like normal mugs
他们看起来不像普通的杯子
they rise up above the rest
他们比一般的好太多
and that's possible
很有可能
so maybe finding some more normal mugs
所以下次你可以找一些正常的杯子
your computer could actually figured out the difference
这样电脑可能更容易辨别
or maybe just more images more data
或者多试几次 多加一些数据
of these super cool cups in these supercool cars
多试一些酷杯子 酷车的图片
such as the Batmobile
比如说蝙蝠车
it could help machine learning do better
这可以让机器学习的更好
but as we see this is a really niche kind of thing
但是我们也看到 这是一件很酷的事
we can do here right we can have two things
我们有两样东西 我们就可以做点什么
the computer doesn't know a car doesn't know what a cup is
计算机并不知道车 杯子是什么东西
but it's able to put them in these boxes
但是它能把它们放进盒子里去
very cool
非常酷
so it's exciting that a computer
计算机根本不知道它在做什么
doesn't really know what it's
这让人激动
doing this is kind of clustering but
这是一种聚类
it's sort of  we're not gonna get
但是其实也有所出入
into details it's a type of clustering
我们今天不会讲聚类的细节
and clustering is amazing because it
聚类非常奇妙 因为
allows you to do some really crazy things
它可以让你做非常疯狂的事
again this gets complicated when
当我想要细说的时候
I can go into the complications
这些概念就会变得很复杂
but it can do so amazing things and you never
但是计算机可以做很多事情
have to know what's going on
而且你根本不需要知道究竟发生了什么
like the computers need to know exactly
但是电脑准确地知道
what's happening and to sometimes
发生了什么 有时候
lighted to you which is super cool
它们会启发你 超级酷
clustering is amazing
聚类很神奇
but here we see that weird with a differentiate
在今天的项目中 我们看到分类
put into two separate boxes cars and cups
将杯子与车分为两类
so enjoy yourself a nice cup of coffee or
去喝一杯咖啡
milk or chocolate sauce
或者是牛奶 或者是巧克力
how about hot chocolate that makes more sense
热巧克力就更好了
so once again this is Walker Stipe from
我是沃克
Palo Alto education hoping that you have an
来自Palo Alto教育
absolutely wonderful there thank you
希望你度过愉快的一天 谢谢